A Guide to the Deeds from the Virginia Land Office records, 1655-1901
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Deeds from the Virginia Land Office records, 1655-1901
The Library of Virginia
LOI 11
.3 cu. ft. (1 box)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession LOI 11 transferred by the Secretary of the Commonwealth, 1948.
Scope and Content
These records contain copies of deeds recorded in the counties of location and probably submitted to the Land Office in cases involving either land disputes or requests for inclusive grants. Information on the outside cover does not indicate the origin of the copy in the Land Office files. Most of the deeds involve land in the western counties of the commonwealth. The deeds are from the years 1655; 1788; 1792; 1795; 1797; 1799; 1801-1803; 1805-1807; 1809; 1812; 1814; 1817-1820; 1822; 1825; 1827; 1829-1832; 1834-1841; 1843-1844; 1848-1849; 1851; 1853-1854; 1856-1857; 1863; 1865; 1867-1869; 1871; 1874-1875; 1878-1881; 1886; 1888-1892; 1895-1896; 1899-1901.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Deeds by grantor, 1655-1901.
Series II. Deeds by grantee, 1820-1890.
Arranged alphabetically by surname.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Virginia. Land Office
Subjects:
Right of property -- Virginia.
Genre and Form Terms:
Deeds -- Virginia.; State government records.
Contents List
- Series 1. Deeds by grantor, 1655-1901., Extent: .2 cu. ft. (2 folders).
  Alphabetical
  - Austin, Stephen F., 1831 Mar. 14. (Folder 1)
  - Bailey, W.H., 1878 Dec. 30. (Folder 1)
  - Baskerville, John B., 1869 Apr. (Folder 1)
  - Beason, Isaac, 1801 Sep. 11. (Folder 1)
  - Booth, William C., 1848 Dec. 22. (Folder 1)
  - Breedlove, Henry, 1849 Jan. 24. (Folder 1)
  - Caldwell, William and Polly, 182 June 15. (Folder 1)
  - Caputo, Daniel, 1820 March 25. (Folder 1)
  - Caputo, Daniel, 1822 May 1. (Folder 1)
  - Carpenter, John C., 1849 Sep. 14. (Folder 1)
  - Carr, John, 1849 Oct. 27. (Folder 1)
  - Carter, Bernard M., 1830 June 19. (Folder 1)
  - Childe, Edward Vernon, 1832 May 10. (Folder 1)
  - Clyburn, Nancy, 1819 Feb. 01. (Folder 1)
  - Clyburn, William and Barbara, 1835 Oct. 08. (Folder 1)
  - Clybourne, Sebastian, 1843 Feb. 18. (Folder 1)
  - Clybourn, William, 1849 Mar. 31. (Folder 1)
  - Cromer, C. D., 1890 Aug. 28. (Folder 1)
  - Cromer, C.D. and Sarah C., 1891 June 28. (Folder 1)
  - Danter, Jacob and Catherine, 1812 Aug. 10. (Folder 1)
  - Danter, Jacob and Catherine, 1812 June 09. (Folder 1)
  - Effinger, W. M., 1888 Apr. 28. (Folder 1)
  - Farley, Jesse, 1809 Sep. 12. (Folder 1)
  - Farley, Judah, 1809 Aug. 18. (Folder 1)
  - Farley, Clay, 1803 Oct. 11. (Folder 1)
  - Farley, Clay and Lettice, 1820 Feb. 20. (Folder 1)
  - Farley, Jesse and Betsey, 1809 Sep. 12. (Folder 1)
  - Fleming, John, 1795 Mar. 04. (Folder 1)
  - Fuller, John and Esther, 1807 Feb. 10. (Folder 1)
  - Gray, Cary and Rebecca, 1857 Dec. 04. (Folder 1)
  - Hale, C. and Adeline, 1884 Sep. 30. (Folder 1)
  - Harman, Adam, 1829 Aug. 10. (Folder 1)
  - Helvey, Peter, 1817 OCt. 25. (Folder 1)
  - Helvey, Peter, 1825 Sep. 21. (Folder 1)
  - Hall, Adaline, 1895 May 15. (Folder 1)
  - Johnson, John R., 1901 Mar. 05. (Folder 1)
  - Kinder, Jacob and Elizabeth, 1799 Jan. 25. (Folder 1)
  - Kinder, Jacob and Elizabeth, 1805 Oct. 02. (Folder 1)
  - Kinsley, R. H. and Elmira, 1892 Feb. 01. (Folder 1)
  - Kirk, John, and Elias Harman, 1840 Sep. 01. (Folder 1)
  - Kirk, John and Peggy, 1838 Feb. 15. (Folder 1)
  - Kirk, John and wife, 1840 Sep. 01. (Folder 1)
  - Kirk, John, and others, 1844 Mar. 26. (Folder 1)
  - Kirk, Lorenzo, 1849 Dec. 24. (Folder 1)
  - Lareau, Isaac, 1874 Apr. 01. (Folder 2)
  - Lee, Charles C., 1839 Apr. 02. (Folder 2)
  - Lee, Henry, 1832 July 04. (Folder 2)
  - Lee, Sidney Smith, and Robert E. Lee, 1832 Apr. 06. (Folder 2)
  - Leedy, Joseph and Sally, 1853 June 13. (Folder 2)
  - Lindamond, Daniel and Eliza, 1853 Feb. 10. (Folder 2)
  - Lucas, J. Brown and Luvinia C., 1899 Nov. 25. (Folder 2)
  - Lucas, J. Brown and Luvinia C., 1900 Sep. 01. (Folder 2)
  - McMahon, Thomas, 1888 Feb. 18. (Folder 2)
  - McGavoch, Hugh Jr., 1820 Mar. 27. (Folder 2)
  - McGavock, Lysander and Elizabeth, and William D. Crockett, 1806 Aug. 19. (Folder 2)
  - Marshall, William S., 1832 Apr. 17. (Folder 2)
  - Meekes, John, 1655 Aug. 20. (Folder 2)
  - Montgomery, Joseph, 1814 Oct. 01. (Folder 2)
  - Newlee, Robert G., 1883 Mar. 27. (Folder 2)
  - O'Neal, John and Jane, 1820 July 04. (Folder 2)
  - Peck, Charles D. and Rachel, 1854 Feb. 10. (Folder 2)
  - Peck, Jacob and Molinda, 1827 Mar. 17. (Folder 2)
  - Pepper, James, 1797 June 13. (Folder 2)
  - Phlegan, Archer A., 1895 Nov. 14. (Folder 2)
  - Rader, Henry and Catharine, 1802 Jan. 11. (Folder 2)
  - Rader, Henry and Catharine, 1802 May 10. (Folder 2)
  - Richard, Giles, 1818 May 26. (Folder 2)
  - Rickey, Joseph and Elizabeth, 1818 May 11. (Folder 2)
  - Schaefer, T. F. and Laura, 1900 Dec. 12. (Folder 2)
  - Smith, W. D. and Alice G., 1896 Feb. 27. (Folder 2)
  - Sprinkle, Henry, 1838 Oct. 24. (Folder 2)
  - Spencer, Howard and Martha J., 1881 Jan. 12. (Folder 2)
  - Stewart, Samuel and Sallie, 1901 Oct. 10. (Folder 2)
  - Straw, Leonard, 1834 Sep. 13. (Folder 2)
  - Surface, C. W., 1883 Dec. 22. (Folder 2)
  - Surface, Jacob and wife; George Lurdow and wife; Michael Surface and wife; Philip Ribble and wife; and George W. Surface and wife; 1837 Sep. 04. (Folder 2)
  - Tarter, Peter and Elizabeth, 1795 Aug. 02. (Folder 2)
  - Thompson, William, 1792 May 26. (Folder 2)
  - Thompson, William, 1788 Oct. 25. (Folder 2)
  - Wallace, John H. and Martha, 1840 Oct. 01. (Folder 2)
  - Yost, James L., and Benjamin R. Floyd, 1851 Jan. 20. (Folder 2)
- Series II. Deeds by Grantee, 1820-1890., Extent: .1 cu. ft. (1 folder)
  - Couch, William and Rachel, 1820 Feb. 11.
  - Copenhaver, John and Susannah, 1836 Sep. 01.
  - Cornull, David, 1836 Oct. 11.
  - Gray, James, 1857 Dec. 04.
  - Gray, James, 1863 May 06.
  - Gray, James, 1863 May 06.
  - Gray, James, 1865 Dec. 27.
  - Gray, James, 1871 Apr. 29.
  - Gray, James, 1875 Jan. 26.
  - Gruff, Franklin, 1875 Feb. 25.
  - Proffit, Joseph P. and Mary; George and Nancy J. Young; and Jacob Smith; 1875 Apr. 26.
  - Proffit, Joseph P., and George Young, 1875 Feb. 02.
  - Proffit, J. P., 1880 Apr. 05.
  - Proffit, J. P., 1880, Aug. 09.
  - Ring, Martin, 1827 Oct. 22.
  - Ring, Jefferson, 1868 July 01.
  - Ring, Martin, 1837 Feb. 15.
  - Ring, Martin, 1836 Aug. 20.
  - Simmons, Obediah, 1856 Aug. 11.
  - Simmons, Obediah, 1867 Mar. 30.
  - Simmons, Obediah, 1879 Apr. 19.
  - Simmons, Obediah, 1879 Mar. 03.
  - Simmons, Obediah, 1880 Apr. 08.
  - Simmons, Obediah, 1880 Feb. 06.
  - Simmons, Obediah, 1880 Apr. 29.
  - Simmons, Obediah, 1886 Jan. 14.
  - Simmons, Obediah, 1890 Feb. 12.